Finding Aid for the The Papers of Edmund M. Morgan, Jr. (1878-1966)
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Edmund M. Morgan, Jr. Paper
1906-1964
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0304
17.09 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
Edmund M. Morgan, Jr., was born on November 11, 1878, in Mineral Ridge, Ohio. After graduating from Ohio public schools, he attended Harvard University. He received the Bachelor of Arts in 1902, the Master of Arts in 1903 and a Bachelor of Laws in 1905. He later completed another Masters degree at Yale (1919). On April 26, 1911, he married Elsie Sears Smith. They had two children, Roberta Mary and Edmund Sears Morgan.
Morgan began his career by practicing law with Coryate Wilson in Duluth, Minnesota, from 1905 to 1912. While in Duluth, he also served as both assistant and acting city attorney (1908-1910) and as special counsel to the Duluth Charter Commission. He joined the faculty of the University of Minnesota Law School in 1912 and served until 1917. From 1917 to 1925, he was a member of the Yale Law School faculty. He actually began his career at Yale with a brief hiatus, however, serving the United States Army as an assistant to the Judge Advocate General from 1917 to 1919, holding the ranks of Major and Lieutenant Colonel.
Morgan left Yale for Harvard in 1925, serving as Royall Professor of Law until he reached mandatory retirement age in 1950. During the summers, he taught at Columbia, North Carolina, Kansas, Colorado, Texas, Washington, Stanford, and Southern California. In 1936-37 and 1942-45, he was Acting Dean of the Harvard Law School. Upon his retirement, he joined the faculty of the Vanderbilt University Law School and was named Rand Professor of Law in 1951. He taught at Vanderbilt until approximately 1962.
From 1935 to approximately 1962, Morgan served as editorial director for the Foundation Press, a major publisher of legal scholarship and teaching materials. During the 1940s and 1950s, he was involved in several important legal reform efforts. From 1935 to 1956, he served on the Advisory Committee of the U.S. Supreme Court on Rules of Civil Procedure, drafting the original set of rules adopted by the Committee. He served the war effort from 1942 to 1945 by chairing the War Shipping Panel of the War Labor Board. In the early 1950s, he chaired the committee that drafted a Uniform Code of Military Justice. Also in the 1950s, he served as a consultant for the territory of Puerto Rico and the State of Israel, developing codes of civil procedure for each. In the course of his career, Morgan authored or co-authored six books and wrote over 100 articles for professional journals. He remained a keen and active scholar almost until the time of his death in Nashville in January 1966, at the age of 87.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Edmund M. Morgan, Jr., date from approximately 1906 to 1964 and document his lengthy and distinguished career as an attorney, a legal scholar, a teacher, and a public servant. The bulk of the collection dates from the 1940s and 1950s. Extensive correspondence, Morgan's own writings, and papers related to his professional activities provide insight into his scholarship and record his part in such important proceedings as the simplification of the federal rules for civil procedure and the modernization of the code of military justice. Other materials reflect his role in the development of rules for civil procedure in Puerto Rico and Israel. An extensive file of course materials documents
Morgan's approach to teaching the law. The Morgan Papers are arranged in seven series:
Biographical and Personal Papers
Correspondence
Writings
Professional Activities and Service
Course Materials
Cases
Collected Writings
Series Descriptions
Series I: Biographical and Personal, 1906-63, nd (.35 cu.ft.)
Biographical sketches, resumes, personal financial and legal documents, memorabilia such as certificates and original cartoons, and photographs. Of particular interest is a manuscript autobiographical sketch written for the Fiftieth Anniversary Report of the Harvard Class of 1902. Arranged alphabetically by document type.
Series II: Correspondence, c. 1906-1964, nd (6.00 cu.ft.)
Consists primarily of professional correspondence dating from the 1930s to the 1950s. Documents Morgan's scholarly and professional activities, especially his work as editorial director of the Foundation Press. Includes significant correspondence with Supreme Court Justice Felix Frankfurter, Puerto Rico Chief Justice A.C. Snyder, and New Jersey Supreme Court Justice Arthur Vanderbilt. Also includes autograph letters from President Dwight D. Eisenhower, Senator John F. Kennedy, Senator Estes Kefauver, and Supreme Court Justice Byron White. Arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
Series III: Writings, 1927-62 (1.00 cu.ft.)
Notes, drafts, and published versions of books, speeches, and articles by Morgan. Arranged alphabetically by title.
Series IV: Professional Activities and Service, 1937-60 (3.00 cu.ft.)
Reports, notes, publications, and correspondence regarding activities engaged in by Morgan, primarily as a service to the nation or to the legal profession, but in some instances as a paid consultant. Includes information related to the revision of the federal rules for civil procedure and the development of a Uniform Code of Military Justice, as well as to the development of rules of civil procedure for Puerto Rico and Israel. Arranged by subject or by name of organization served.
Series V: Course Materials, 1926-62, nd (2.75 cu.ft.)
Lecture notes and handouts for courses in civil procedure, evidence, jurisprudence, legal history, and trial and appellate practice, dating primarily from Morgan's Harvard and Vanderbilt years. Includes the full text of weekly lectures delivered for a Harvard course in jurisprudence during the academic year 1926-27. Arranged alphabetically by course.
Series VI: Cases, 1942-61, nd (.35 cu.ft.)
Depositions, briefs, and decisions for a variety of cases that Morgan apparently used for his courses or his own research or for which he served counsel in a consulting capacity. Includes information regarding the 1952 prosecution of Alger Hiss. Arranged alphabetically by title of case.
Series VII: Collected Writings, 1914-62 (.25 cu.ft.)
Typescripts or published versions of articles, speeches, and publications on legal issues. Arranged alphabetically by title within each document type.
- Series I -- Biographical and Personal
  - Biographical sketches and resumes, 1942, 1946, 1949, 1951-52, 1956, 1961, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Financial, 1908, c. 1950s (Box 1)
  - Legal documents, 1911, 1938, 1952, 1954, 1960, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1)
    - Bar associations, nd, 1953-54, 1957-59 (Box 1)
    - Cartoons, 1936, 1955, nd (Box 1)
    - Certificates, nd, 1948-49, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1957, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Harvard Law School, nd, 1954-56 (Box 1)
    - Harvard University, nd, 1906, 1927, 1936, 1938, 1949-50, 1953, 1956-57 (Box 1)
    - Harvard University -- Tercentenary, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Miscellany, nd, 1924, 1926, 1933, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, nd (Box 1)
- Series II -- Correspondence
  - A-Am (Box 2)
  - An-Ay (Box 2)
  - Ba-Bre (Box 2)
  - Ca-Ch (Box 2)
  - Ci-Cu (Box 2)
  - Casebook correspondence, 4th ed., 1955-56 (Box 2)
  - Casebook correspondence, 1957-63 (Box 2)
  - Clark, Charles E., 1949-59 (Box 2)
  - Columbia University lectures, 1954-56 (Box 2)
  - Conant, J.B., 1935-36 (Box 2)
  - D (Box 2)
  - E (Box 2)
  - F (Box 2)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, nd, 1933-63 (Box 2)
  - Ga-Gi (Box 2)
  - Gl-Gu (Box 2)
  - Goodrich, Herbert F., 1953-54, 1961-62 (Box 2)
  - Griswold, Erwin, 1931-62 (Box 2)
  - Ha (Box 2)
  - He-Hu (Box 2)
  - Harvard, 1945-64 (Box 2)
  - Harvard Law School, 1948-52 (Box 2)
  - Harvard-Yale, re: employment, 1918-50 (Box 2)
  - Hiss, Alger, Case, 1951-63 (Box 2)
- Series II -- Correspondence
  - I (Box 3)
  - J (Box 3)
  - K (Box 3)
  - La (Box 3)
  - LeMann - Levi (Box 3)
  - Levin, A. Leo - Lewis, William Draper (Box 3)
  - Li-Lu (Box 3)
  - Maggs - Maguire (Box 3)
  - Maguire - Mayers (Box 3)
  - Mc (Box 3)
  - Me-Mo (Box 3)
  - Mu (Box 3)
  - Magazines (Box 3)
  - Morgan - Personal, nd, 1950-63 (2f) (Box 3)
  - N (Box 3)
  - O (Box 3)
  - Osborn, Albert S. and Albert D. (son), 1935-40, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Pa-Pi (Box 3)
  - Po-Pu (Box 3)
  - Pound, Roscoe, 1928-63 (Box 3)
  - President's Commission on Internal Security and Individual Rights, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Puerto Rico, 1953-61 (Box 3)
  - Q (Box 3)
  - Ra-Ri (Box 3)
  - Ro-Ru (Box 3)
  - Recommendations, A-Z (3f) (Box 3)
- Series III -- Correspondence
  - Retirement congratulations, 1949-50 (Box 4)
  - Rules, Procedure & Evidence (Advisory committees, etc.), 1958-61 (Box 4)
  - Sa-Sk (Box 4)
  - Sl-Sp (Box 4)
  - St-Sw (Box 4)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti, 1947-63 (Box 4)
  - Students, 1960-61 (Box 4)
  - T (Box 4)
  - Texas, Univ. of, nd, 1944-45 (Box 4)
  - Thurston, Prof. & Mrs. Edward S., 1928-48 (Box 4)
  - U (Box 4)
  - V (Box 4)
  - Vanderbilt, Arthur, 1945-57 (Box 4)
  - Vanderbilt University, nd, 1953-61 (Box 4)
  - Vanderbilt University -- James Lawson Case and Student Disciplinary Procedure, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Wa-Wh (Box 4)
  - Wi (Box 4)
  - Wo-Wy (Box 4)
  - Weinstein, Jack B., 1953-62 (Box 4)
  - Y-Z (Box 4)
  - Sender not identified, nd, 1936, 1954-55, 1963 (Box 4)
- Series II -- Correspondence
  - Foundation Press -- Authors/Editors (Box 5)
    - A (Box 5)
    - B (Box 5)
    - Ca-Ch (Box 5)
    - Co-Cu (Box 5)
    - [re] Chafee, et. al. (Box 5)
    - D (Box 5)
    - E (Box 5)
    - F (Box 5)
    - Ga-Go (Box 5)
    - Gr-Gu (Box 5)
    - Hackley - Haskins (Box 5)
    - Hanna & MacLachlan (Box 5)
    - Hawkland - Honnold (Box 5)
    - I-J-K (Box 5)
    - L (Box 5)
    - Leach (Box 5)
    - Ma-Mc (Box 5)
    - Me-Mu (Box 5)
    - N-O (Box 5)
    - P (Box 5)
    - R (Box 5)
    - Sa-Sc (Box 5)
    - Se-So (Box 5)
    - St-Su (Box 5)
- Series II -- Correspondence
  - Foundation Press -- Authors/Editors (cont'd) (Box 6)
    - T (Box 6)
    - V (Box 6)
    - W (Box 6)
  - Foundation Press -- General (Box 6)
    - A (Box 6)
    - B (Box 6)
    - Benton, Donald S., June 1957-1960 (2f) (Box 6)
    - C (Box 6)
    - D (Box 6)
    - Darr, Loren, nd, 1933-37, 1939-41, 1948-64 (20f) (Box 6)
    - F (Box 6)
    - G-J (Box 6)
    - K (Box 6)
- Series II -- Correspondence
  - Foundation Press -- General (cont'd) (Box 7)
    - L (Box 7)
    - Levins, Richard T., 1949-56 (3f) (Box 7)
    - M (Box 7)
    - Magill, Roswell, 1933-48 (Box 7)
    - Maguire, John M., 1933-51 (Box 7)
    - P (Box 7)
    - R (Box 7)
    - Read, M.E., 1933-37 (2f) (Box 7)
    - S (Box 7)
    - T (Box 7)
    - Vogel, F.M., 1937-39 (Box 7)
    - W-Y (Box 7)
  - Foundation Press -- Miscellany, c. 1942-61 (3f) (Box 7)
- Series III -- Writings
  - Unidentified notes and fragments, nd (Box 8)
  - Untitled, nd (Box 8)
  - Untitled: (Box 8)
    - Buffalo, NY, 28 May 1938 (Box 8)
    - Benchers, 6 May 1939 (Box 8)
    - American Law Institute, Washington, D.C., 12 May 1939 (Box 8)
    - Ohio Bar Association, 20 Oct 1939 (Box 8)
    - Boston College Law School Tenth Anniversary, 9 Apr 1940 (Box 8)
    - Lincoln, Nebraska, ?? Dec 1941 (Box 8)
    - Harvard Club of Houston, TX, ?? May 1945 (Box 8)
    - New Bedford Bar Association, 20 May 1946 (Box 8)
    - Mississippi, 13 Dec 1946 (Box 8)
    - Harvard Law School Alumni, Pittsburgh, ?? Mar 1949 (Box 8)
    - Brandeis Society, Philadelphia, 21 Apr 1949 (Box 8)
    - Outline of lectures, Institute for Practicing, 10 Oct 1952 (Box 8)
    - Lawyers on Current Legal Problems, Vanderbilt (Box 8)
    - Law School, Nashville, TN (Box 8)
    - Annual meeting of the National Conference of, 24 May 1956 (Box 8)
    - Judicial Councils, Washington, D.C. (Box 8)
    - South Carolina Institute, ?? Mar 1958 (Box 8)
    - University of Missouri Law School Law Day, 1 May 1959 (Box 8)
    - Tennessee Bar Association, Jackson, TN, 26 Feb 1960 (Box 8)
    - Civitans, Nashville, TN, 18 Sep 1962 (Box 8)
  - Books (Box 8)
    - Legacy of Sacco and Vanzetti -- Notes, clippings, miscellany, 1927, 1936, 1947 (Box 8)
  - 1959, nd (Box 8)
    - Evidence: Cases and Materials (Box 8)
  - Folder A-C (Box 8)
  - "Admissions," nd (4 separate speeches) (Box 8)
  - "American Law Institute's Code of Evidence," Hershey, PA, 26 Sep 1942 (Box 8)
  - "Appeal and Error," nd (Box 8)
  - "Assumed Risks," nd (Box 8)
  - "Code of Evidence," Federal Judicial Conference of the 4th Circuit, Asheville, NC, 21 June 1941 (2 drafts) (Box 8)
  - "Codification of Evidence," Centenary, New York University Law School, 29 Sept 1948 (Box 8)
  - "Comments on the Code of Evidence," American Judicature Society, 3 Nov 1943 (Box 8)
  - Columbia lectures, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Folder E-H (Box 8)
  - "Evidence," nd (Box 8)
  - "Exceptions to the Hearsay Rule -- On What Theory?," nd (Box 8)
  - "Fresh Complaint in Rape as Hearsay," nd (Box 8)
  - "Fundamental Assumptions," Vermont Bar Association, 3 Oct 1945 (Box 8)
  - "Future Interests Restatement -- Open Letter to the Reporter," (Box 8)
    Ann Arbor, Michigan, 3 Oct 1933
  - "Future of the Law of Evidence," Texas Law Review, 25 Jan 1951 (Box 8)
  - "A Gentleman Departs," [obit of Joseph Warren of Harvard Law (Box 8)
    School], Harvard Law Review, October 1942
  - "The Hearsay Rule," Columbus, 1941 (Box 8)
  - "The Hearsay Rule," Toledo, nd (Box 8)
  - "Hearsay -- What is It?," nd (Box 8)
  - "An Honest Confession May be Good for the Soul, But Not for the FBI," nd (Box 8)
  - Folder I-O (Box 8)
  - "Impartial Medical Testimony -- A Report by a Special Committee of the Bar of the City of New York,", 1956 (Box 8)
  - "International Codification of Evidence," nd (Box 8)
  - "The Judge as a Social Philosopher," nd (Box 8)
  - "Jurisdiction and Venue," nd (Box 8)
  - "The Law and the Average Man," nd (Box 8)
  - "The Lawyer and the Community," nd (Box 8)
  - "Lectures Introductory to the Study of Law," University of Minnesota, nd (Box 8)
  - "The Medical Witness," nd (Box 8)
  - "The Medical Witness," Vanderbilt, April 1959 (Box 8)
  - "Outline and Suggestions for Teachers, Cases on Evidence,", 1937 (Box 8)
  - Folder P (Box 8)
  - "Pleading," nd (Box 8)
  - "Preliminary Consideration," Arkansas Bar Association, Hot Springs, 12 May 1944 (Box 8)
  - "The President and the Supreme Court," Arlington [Va.?], 30 April 1937 (Box 8)
  - "Professional Ethics," [outline], 18 Oct 1946 (2 drafts) (Box 8)
  - "Proposed Reforms in the Law of Evidence," nd (2 drafts) (Box 8)
  - Folder R (Box 8)
  - "Recent Legal Developments," Vanderbilt University, 19 Oct 1956 (Box 8)
  - "Reform in Procedure and Evidence," nd (2 copies) (Box 8)
  - "Relation Between Pleading Discovery and Pre-Trial Procedure," nd (Box 8)
  - Review -- Some Problems of Equity by Zechariah Chafee, University of Michigan Law Society, 1950 (Box 8)
  - "Rule of Reason in Evidence," nd (Box 8)
  - "Rule of Reason in Hearsay," nd (Box 8)
  - "Rules of Evidence -- Substantive or Procedural?," nd (Box 8)
  - Folder S-T (Box 8)
  - "A Selection of Cases on Evidence at the Common Law,", 1933 (Box 8)
  - "Some Needed Reforms in the Law," nd (Box 8)
  - "Some Observations Upon the Rules of Evidence," nd (Box 8)
  - "Some Remarks Upon Legal Ethics," New Haven Bar Association, January 1934 (Box 8)
  - "State Law in Federal Courts," Vanderbilt Law Institute, 1 November 1957 (2 copies) (Box 8)
  - [intro to] The Strange Case of Alger Hiss by The Earl Jowitt, nd (Box 8)
  - "Suggested Remedy for Obstructions to Expert Testimony by Rules of Evidence,", 1943 (Box 8)
  - "That Glorious Mystery -- The Law of Evidence," Louisiana State Bar Institute, May 1957 (2 copies) (Box 8)
  - Folder U-W (Box 8)
  - "The Uniform Rules and the Model Code," nd (2 copies) (Box 8)
  - "The Uniform Rules of Evidence," Federation of Insurance Counsel, August 1959 (Box 8)
  - "Uniform Rules of Evidence," -- Notes, nd (Box 8)
  - "Uniform Rules of Evidence," -- Mississippi Junior Bar Institute, December 1957 (Box 8)
  - "Use of Evidence to Establish Facts in Law," nd (Box 8)
  - "We are Met on Form 1040," nd [taxpayer's parody of Lincoln's Gettysburg Address] (Box 8)
  - "What is Hearsay?," nd (Box 8)
  - "What is Hearsay? -- Hearsay and Non-Hearsay," nd (Box 8)
- Series IV -- Professional Activities and Service
  - American Bar Association, 1943-50, 1954, 1965 (Box 9)
  - American Law Institute (Box 9)
    - General, 1941-52 (Box 9)
    - Basic Problems of Evidence, 1957-63 (Box 9)
    - Model Code Institutes, alphabetical by cities or state bar associations, 1941-42 (5f) (Box 9)
  - Association of American Law Schools, 1947-50, 1959-60 (2f) (Box 9)
  - Consulting, 1947-49 (Box 9)
  - International Congress of Comparative Law, Paris (1954), 1953 (Box 9)
  - Military Justice, Uniform Code (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, nd, 1948-50, 1952-54 (4f) (Box 9)
    - Draft manual, nd (Box 9)
    - Miscellany, nd, 1948, 1952 (Box 9)
    - Notes, nd (Box 9)
    - Press releases, 1950, 1953 (Box 9)
    - Senate and House Bills, 1949 (Box 9)
    - Statements, nd, 1949 (Box 9)
    - Text, nd (Box 9)
    - Text -- Proposed revisions, nd (Box 9)
  - Rules for Civil Procedure, Federal Supreme Court Advisory Committee (Box 9)
    - Clark, Charles E., 1937-46 (Box 9)
    - Mitchell, William D., 1937-50 (Box 9)
    - 1935-50 (3f) (Box 9)
- Series IV -- Professional Activities and Service
  - Rules for Civil Procedure, Federal Supreme Court Advisory Committee (cont'd) (Box 10)
    - 1935-50 (2f) (Box 10)
    - 1951 - June 1953 (Box 10)
    - July - December 1953 (Box 10)
    - January - April 1954 (Box 10)
    - May - October 1954 (Box 10)
    - November 1-15, 1954 (Box 10)
    - November 16-25, 1954 (Box 10)
    - November 26-29, 1954 (Box 10)
    - November 30 - December 31, 1954 (Box 10)
    - January 3 - March 1, 1955 (Box 10)
    - March 5 - April 8, 1955 (Box 10)
    - April 15, 1955 (Box 10)
    - April 16 - May 20, 1955 (Box 10)
    - June 1, 1955 - 1956 (Box 10)
- Series IV -- Professional Activities and Service
  - Rules for Civil Procedure, Federal Supreme Court Advisory Committee (cont'd) (Box 11)
    - No dates (2f) (Box 11)
  - Rules for Civil Procedure, Puerto Rico (Box 11)
    - Draft, nd (2f) (Box 11)
    - Final text, October 1954 (Box 11)
    - Notes and misc., nd (2f) (Box 11)
    - Rules of Evidence, Puerto Rico, 1958 (Box 11)
  - Subcommittee on Practice and Procedure, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Uniform Rules of Evidence (Committee of the American Law Institute), 1952-53 (2f) (Box 11)
  - Uniform Rules of Evidence -- Israel, nd, 1953 (2f) (Box 11)
- Series V -- Course Materials
  - Civil Procedure, c. 1950-62 (4f) (Box 12)
  - Evidence, c. 1951-62 (9f) (Box 12)
  - Evidence -- Notes, nd (3f) (Box 12)
- Series V -- Course Materials
  - Evidence -- Notes for proposed primer, nd (Box 13)
  - Harvard Law Exams, 1931-48 (3f) (Box 13)
  - Jurisprudence -- Classroom lectures, 1926-27 (2f) (Box 13)
  - Legal History [text from medieval England?] (Box 13)
    - Action Upon the Case (Box 13)
    - Assise of Last Presentation (Box 13)
    - Assise of Morte D'Ancestor (Box 13)
    - Assise of Novel Disseisin (Box 13)
    - Assise Utrum (Box 13)
    - Debt (Box 13)
    - Detinue (Box 13)
    - The Tremor (Box 13)
    - Trespass (Box 13)
    - Writ of Covenant (Box 13)
    - Writ of Entry (Box 13)
    - Writ of Right (Box 13)
    - Wrongs (Box 13)
  - Legal History -- unidentified, nd (5f) (Box 13)
- Series V -- Course Materials
  - Misc., c. 1940-60 (Box 14)
  - Mulvaney v. Lever, nd (3f) (Box 14)
  - Systematic Social Science, nd (Box 14)
  - Techniques in Legal Argument, 1934 (2f) (Box 14)
  - Trial and Appellate Practice, nd (3f) (Box 14)
  - Unidentified, nd (2f) (Box 14)
  - Vanderbilt Curriculum Committee, 1958-62 (Box 14)
- Series VI -- Cases
  - Brookside Theatre Corp. v. Twentieth Century Fox, nd (2f) (Box 14)
  - Margo Brown v. Pelican State Theatre Corp., nd (Box 14)
  - George M. Bryne v. U.S.A., 1952 (Box 14)
  - Farnsworth (Guam -- Air Force Special Consultant), 1947-51 (Box 14)
  - Raymond J. Lamping v. U.S.A., 1942 (2f) (Box 14)
  - Lever Brothers, 1943-46, dn (2f) (Box 14)
- Series VI -- Cases
  - Lever Brothers, 1943-46, nd (1f) (Box 15)
  - Alyce Morgan v. The Bulletin Co., 1949 (Box 15)
  - Florence M. Nuttall v. The REading Co., nd (Box 15)
  - United States v. Alger Hiss, 1952 (Box 15)
  - United States v. Proctor and Gamble, 1942 (Box 15)
  - United States v. Salvatore Annunziato, 1961 (Box 15)
- Series VII -- Collected Writings
  - Articles/Essays (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 15)
  - Angell, Walter F. "A Providence Lawyer at the Caillaux Trial,", 1914 (Box 15)
  - Bergdoll case, review of testimony, nd (Box 15)
  - Blaustein, Albert P. "NYCLA -- Giant of Bar Associations," nd (Box 15)
  - Braverman, Shelley. "Procedure and the Expert Witness," Journal of Forensic Sciences Vol. 7, No., 3, July 1962 (Box 15)
  - "The Case Method," nd (Box 15)
  - Cheatham, Elliott E. "The Inculcation of Professional Standards and the Functions of the Lawyer," Tennessee Law Review, June 1951 (Box 15)
  - Clark, Charles E. "'Clarifying' Amendments to the Federal Rules?" (Box 15)
  - ----------------. Foreward to Pittoni's Brief Writing, 1954 (Box 15)
  - "Dictum or Decision," c, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Dienner, John A. "Patent Law Associations," Journal of the Patent Office Society, November 1950 (Box 15)
  - Goodrich, Herbert F. "The Story of the American Law Institute," Washington University Law Quarterly, June 1951 (Box 15)
  - Hammelman, H.A. "Hearsay Evidence, A Comparison," The Law Quarterly Review, January 1951 (Box 15)
  - "How to Teach Law,", 1951 (Box 15)
  - Johnstone, Quentin. "Law School and Legal Aid Clinics," Journal of Legal Education, Vol. 3, 1951 (Box 15)
  - Articles/Essays (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 15)
  - Leach, W. Barton, ed. "Langdell Lyrics of 1938," 1938. (Box 15)
  - "Libelous Lyrics Written on Several Laughable Occasions," 1938. (Box 15)
  - McNaughton, John T. "The Privilege Against Self-Incrimination: Its Constitutional Affectation (Box 15)
  - Raison d'Etre and Miscellaneous Implications," Journal of Criminal Law, Criminology, and Police Science, Vol. 51, No. 2, July- August 1960 (Box 15)
  - Michael, Jerome. "The Basic Rules of Pleading," The Record (Bar Association of New York City), Vol. 5, No. 4, April 1950 (Box 15)
  - Morland, John W. "Legal Education in Georgia," Mercer Law Review Vol. 2, No. 2, Spring 1951. (Box 15)
  - Osborn, Albert S. "Science and the Law and Difficulties in Proving Forgery," Virginia Law (Box 15)
  - Review Vol. XVI, No. 5, March 1930 (Box 15)
  - Powell, ?. "Constitutional Metaphors," nd. (Box 15)
  - Seasongood, Murray. "Public Service Lawyers in Local Government," Syracuse Law Review (Box 15)
  - Spring 1951. (Box 15)
  - Sims, Cecil. "Taking the Fifth Amendment -- A Case in Civil Rights," nd. (Box 15)
  - Smith, Reginald Heber. "Loan Plan for Law Students," Quarterly Report (Conference on Personal Finance Law), Vol. 5, No. 3, Summer 1951. (Box 15)
  - "Uniform Commercial Code,", June 1951 (Box 15)
  - Publications (Box 15)
  - Legislative Bulletin (Tennessee Bar Association), Jan-March, 1961 (7 issues) (Box 15)
  - The Mississippi Lawyer, December 6-7, 1957 (Box 15)
  - The Shingle (published by the Philadelphia Bar Association), Vol. XVII, No. 7, October 1954 (Box 15)
  - West Virginia State Bar News, Vol. 1, No. 56, July-August 1959 (Box 15)
  - Speeches and Addresses (Box 15)
  - Caskey, John Fletcher. Remarks before the Evidence Section of the Association of American (Box 15)
  - Law School Teachers, 29 Dec 1953 (Box 15)
  - Chadbourn, James H. "Uniform Rules of Evidence," Hollywood (CA) Bar Association, 19 March 1954 (Box 15)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Remarks at Gettysburg, PA, 19 November ? (Box 15)